Preliminary Guide to the Frederic Lawrence Holmes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Frederic Lawrence Holmes papers
1952-2002
MS 1835
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
The papers document Frederic Lawrence Holmes' research in the history of the life sciences and include audiotapes and transcripts of interviews conducted for his research on Hans Krebs. The files also include materials relating to his work on Matthew Meselson and Frank Stahl on the replication of DNA.
Holmes, Frederic Lawrence, 1932-2003
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Susan E. Holmes, 2004; gift of the estate of Frederic Lawrence Holmes, 2004.
Biographical / Historical
Frederic Lawrence Holmes was born in1932 in Cincinnati, Ohio, and earned a Ph.D. at Harvard University in the history of science. From 1977 until his death on March 27, 2003, he was a full professor in the Section of the History of Medicine in the Yale School of Medicine. He served as master of Jonathan Edwards College from 1983 to 1987. His research and publications focus on topics in history of the life sciences.
Scope and Contents
The papers document Frederic Lawrence Holmes' research in the history of the life sciences and include audiotapes and transcripts of interviews conducted for his research on Hans Krebs. The files also include materials relating to his work on Matthew Meselson and Frank Stahl on the replication of DNA.
Conditions Governing Access
The audiotapes of interviews are unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks. are restricted until processed.
Biochemistry -- History; Science -- History -- Study and teaching; Holmes, Frederic Lawrence, 1932-2003; Krebs, Hans Adolf, Sir, 1900-1981; Meselson, Matthew; Stahl, Franklin W., 1929-; Yale University. Department of the History of Science and Medicine
- Inventory
  - Photographs, notebooks containing transcripts of interviews, 1952, 1976-1981 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, notebooks containing transcripts of interviews, 1952, 1976-1981 (Box 2)
  - Audiotapes of interviews, 1976-1981
    Conditions Governing Access
    The material is unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
    - 1-94 (Box 3)
    - 95-170 (Box 4)
    - Unnumbered (Box 5)
  - Transcripts of interviews with interview questions and correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 6)
  - Transcripts of interviews with interview questions and correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 7)
  - Transcripts of interviews with interview questions and correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence and general files, 1955-1999 (Box 9)
  - Writings and lectures, 1989-2002 (Box 10)